

Sachin Chhabra



SUMMARY

Ph.D. in Computer Science (Arizona State University), specializing in computer vision and label-efficient training of neural networks, with multiple first-author publications and patents. Machine Learning Scientist at Wayfair, designing and deploying large-scale recommendation and forecasting systems.



EDUCATION

Doctor of Philosophy (Ph.D.) in Computer Science, Arizona State University, GPA: 4.0/4.0 Master of Science in Computer Science, Arizona State University, GPA: 3.9/4.0 Bachelor of Technology in Computer Science, Vellore Institute of Technology, India

Aug 2019 - May 2024 Aug 2017 - May 2019 Aug 2009 — Aug 2013



WayFair

WORK EXPERIENCE

Machine Learning Scientist

July 2024 — Present

Mountain View, California

- Developed a recommendation engine for images for improving user product discovery.
- Designed a multi-task neural network for sales forecasting across multiple markets and stages of B2B customers.
- Machine Learning Intern [] WayFair

Summer 2022 & Summer 2023

Boston, Massachusetts

- Automated product color extraction from images using object detection and segmentation based on input query text.
- Designed and implemented a Graph Neural Network (GNN) to build an item-to-item-based recommendation system.
- Machine Learning Intern

May 2020 — Aug 2020

Systems Imagination Tempe, Arizona (Remote)

Processed time series and tabular data using a hybrid neural network to predict covid case counts and risk for the US counties.

Senior Software Engineer

Dec 2013 — Jun 2017

Accenture Bangalore, India - Worked on migration scripts, stored procedures for databases, and wrote SQL queries for ETL transformation logic.

PUBLICATIONS & PATENTS

Full List at Google Scholar



- Chhabra, S. et al. Label Smoothing++: Enhanced Label Regularization for Training Neural Networks. BMVC (2024). [🏶 🚨 📭
- Chhabra, S. et al. PatchRot: Self-Supervised Training of Vision Transformers by Rotation Prediction. BMVC (2024). [🜐 🔼 🗘 🦃
- Chhabra,S. et al. Translation of Partially Paired Images with Generative Adversarial Networks. IEEE EMBS BHI (2024). [💪]
- Chhabra, S. et al. Generative Alignment of Posterior Probabilities for Source-free Domain Adaptation. WACV (2023). [🔀 🔼

PROJECTS & PROFESSIONAL SERVICES

Large Language Model (LLM) from Scratch in PyTorch

[0]

- Implemented GPT3 and LLaMA-2 based Large Language Models (LLM) from scratch in PyTorch with functionalities like Byte-Pair tokenizer, Rotational Positional Embedding (RoPe), SwishGLU, RMSNorm, and Mixture of Experts (MOE).
- Vision Transformer from Scratch in PyTorch [100+★]

 $[\mathbf{O}]$

- Implemented Vision Transformer (ViT) from scratch in PyTorch, including operations like self-attention.
- Various Generative Adversarial Networks (GAN)

 $[\mathbf{O}]$

- Implemented Vanilla-GAN, DCGAN, LSGAN, CGAN, CycleGAN, WGAN, WGAN-GP, and StarGAN for generating/translating images.
- · Research Paper Reviewer

2021 - Present

- Regularly reviewed research papers for CVPR, ICLR, NeurIPS, ICCV, ECCV, AAAI, ICML, BMVC, WACV, and ACM TIST.

X TECHNICAL SKILLS

Python, SQL Programming

ML Frameworks PyTorch, Keras, Scikit-learn, OpenCV

Specialties Deep Learning, Transformers, GANs, GNNs, Computer Vision

Cloud Google Cloud Platform (BigQuery, AI Platform, Dataflow, Composer Airflow)